<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//Apache Software Foundation//DTD XDOC 1.0//EN"
  "http://maven.apache.org/dtd/xdoc_1_0.dtd">
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>SchemaCrawler Lint</title>
    <author email="sualeh@hotmail.com">Sualeh Fatehi</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="SchemaCrawler Lint">
      <subsection name="SchemaCrawler Lint">
        <p>
          SchemaCrawler can analyze and
          <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lint_(software)">lint</a>
          your database to find potential issues. SchemaCrawler Lint can be run using the
          <code>-infolevel=lint</code>
          command-line option.
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Tables with incrementing column names, for example, a table with column names like contact1, contact2 and
            so on can indicate de-normalization. SchemaCrawler Lint will flag such tables with a lint message.</li>
          <li>SchemaCrawler Lint will flag tables with just a single column with a lint message, since this could
            indicate a schema design smell.</li>
          <li>SchemaCrawler Lint will flag tables with no indices with a lint message.</li>
          <li>Tables where the default value is 'NULL' instead of NULL may indicate a error when creating a table.
            SchemaCrawler Lint will flag such tables with a lint message.</li>
          <li>SchemaCrawler Lint will flag tables that have nullable columns in a unique index, with a lint message.
          </li>
          <li>SchemaCrawler Lint will flag tables that have space in table or column names, or names that are reserved
            words in the ANSI SQL standard, with a lint message.
          </li>
        </ul>
        <p>SchemaCrawler Lint also analyzes the database for weak associations. Weak associations are inferred
          associations between tables, similar to forign keys, even if there is no
          foreign key defined in the database
          between the tables. Ruby on Rails table schemes are supported, as well as
          other simple naming conventions.
          Table name prefixes are automatically detected. Weak associations are output
          in the graphs as a dotted line,
          and are also output in the text formats.</p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
