<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//Apache Software Foundation//DTD XDOC 1.0//EN"
  "http://maven.apache.org/dtd/xdoc_1_0.dtd">
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>SchemaCrawler - Readme</title>
    <author
      email="sualeh@hotmail.com">Sualeh Fatehi
    </author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section
      name="Getting Started">
      <subsection
        name="FAQs">
        Before downloading SchemaCrawler, be sure to read the
        <a
          href="faq.html">FAQs
        </a>
        .
      </subsection>
      <subsection
        name="Examples">
        <p>
          The first thing to try after downloading the SchemaCrawler
          distribution is the examples. Several examples on how to use
          SchemaCrawler on the command line, as an ant task or Maven plugin,
          as
          an API, as well as how to use the
          <a
            href="http://velocity.apache.org/">Apache Velocity
          </a>
          (templating) integration and how to create database diagrams with
          <a
            href="http://www.graphviz.org/">Graphviz
          </a>
          are provided in the
          <code>_distrib/examples</code>
          directory.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection
        name="How-tos">
        <p>
          Once you start getting comfortable with SchemaCrawler, and need to
          know more about how to do things, read the
          <a
            href="how-to.html">how-tos
          </a>
          section.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection
        name="Whitepapers and Documentation">
        <p>To read more about SchemaCrawler, you can read:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <a
              href="http://www.devx.com/Java/Article/32443">
              Java API Makes Database Metadata as Easily Accessible as
              POJOs
            </a>
            for an introduction to the SchemaCrawler API. (This article may
            refer to an older release of the SchemaCrawler API, but the
            concepts are the same.)
          </li>
          <li>
            The SchemaCrawler API
            <a
              href="apidocs/index.html">javadocs
            </a>
            .
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section
      name="Building From the Source Code">
      <subsection
        name="ant Build">
        <p>
          The
          <a href="http://ant.apache.org/">ant</a>
          build is a quick build that builds the SchemaCrawler jar
          without running unit tests. Download
          <a
            href="http://ant.apache.org/">ant
          </a>
          and run it from the SchemaCrawler directory. The SchemaCrawler jar
          file will be created in the
          <code>_distrib</code>
          directory. The main targets are
          <code>all.build</code>
          and
          <code>all.clean.</code>
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection
        name="Maven Build">
        <p>
          The Maven build is a more comprehensive build that runs unit tests,
          and can also create the project web-site. Download
          <a
            href="http://maven.apache.org/">Maven 2.0.
          </a>
          Then run
          <code>mvn package</code>
          from the SchemaCrawler directory. The SchemaCrawler distribution
          will
          be created in the
          <code>target</code>
          of the
          <code>distribution</code>
          module.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection
        name="Eclipse">
        <p>
          Before importing the various SchemaCrawler projects into Eclipse, make sure
          that you have a successful Maven build. Maven will download all the
          dependencies needed to build SchemaCrawler. Also, install the
          <a
            href="http://m2eclipse.sonatype.org/">m2eclipse Maven Integration for Eclipse
          </a>
          plugin.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
